<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech Contracting</title>
    <link>http://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tech Contracting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Get in Contact</title>
      <link>http://example.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>http://example.org/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/home/</guid>
      <description>CHEAP LABOR
Contracting has become the new normal in tech, with many large companies having 50% or more of their workforce in contingent roles, and more coming in as shareholders pressure companies to increase their profits every year. Contracting has become a cheap way for companies to size up and down their labor at the expense of people who need work to survive.
WHERE’S THE POWER?
For decades, independent contracting has been touted as the answer to workers moving within a fast-past, high-paying industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid 19 Resources</title>
      <link>http://example.org/resources/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/resources/covid/</guid>
      <description>Working class people across the world are organizing and mobilizing to support each other at the sites of the workplace, housing, and beyond to deal with this new health crisis. When the ruling class fails to take care of us, we will find ways to take care of each other, and organize for even better labor and living conditions. This article features mostly US-based local initiatives and programs to alleviate the effects of the pandemic and its various impacts on workers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History of Contracting</title>
      <link>http://example.org/resources/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/resources/history/</guid>
      <description>TVCs have been around since the beginning of the tech industry
The 1992 Landmark Temp-Worker Microsoft Case
  In 1992, contract &amp;amp; temporary workers at Microsoft filed a lawsuit against being misclassified as independent contractors despite being &amp;ldquo;Perma-temps&amp;rdquo;
  Working full-time or more hours.
  Working alongside full-time employees.
  Despite being labeled as temporary or seasonal workers, many Microsoft contractors were working for the company for many years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know Your Rights</title>
      <link>http://example.org/rights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/rights/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading List</title>
      <link>http://example.org/resources/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/resources/reading/</guid>
      <description>A selection of readings to keep you up to date on contracting in tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://example.org/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/resources/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rights, Retaliation, and HR</title>
      <link>http://example.org/kyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/kyr/</guid>
      <description>YOUR RIGHT TO ORGANIZE AT WORK
In most cases, joining together with your coworkers to improve your working conditions under your contracting company is your legally protected right under the National Labor Relations Act (NLRA) [https://www.nlrb.gov/how-we-work/national-labor-relations-act]. However, certain types of employees (like Independent Contractors on a 1099) do not have these same protections.
To learn more about your workplace organizing right and who is covered, go to https://www.nlrb.gov/rights-we-protect/rights/employee-rights and https://www.nlrb.gov/resources/faq/nlrb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Documentation</title>
      <link>http://example.org/tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/tips/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Start a Job Journal, noting positive and negative comments from supervisors and managers. Keep notes from meetings, schedule changes, etc. Make sure you note when, where, why, etc. Save company memos and pay stubs, ANYTHING that you think will help your case if you must use a government agency to fight the boss.&amp;rdquo; - IWW
All your notes should have the date at the top of each page, and next to any notable action or important statement, jot down the time if possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricks</title>
      <link>http://example.org/tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/tricks/</guid>
      <description>TRICKS THEY’LL PULL ON YOU There are a number of reasons behind why contracting is so lucrative for businesses. Some of these decisions are made behind the scenes, but many others are done face-to-face.
HOURS AND PAY Promising contracted employees a certain amount of compensation and then giving them less when it comes time to sign Try to tell you to work without claiming your hours because it will help you get an FTE position (this is wage theft) Placing a higher volume of work, a greater number of hours, and providing less pay to employees with H1B visas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>