<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rights on Tech Contracting</title>
    <link>/rights/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rights on Tech Contracting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/rights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rights, Retaliation, and HR</title>
      <link>/rights/kyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rights/kyr/</guid>
      <description>YOUR RIGHT TO ORGANIZE AT WORK
In most cases, joining together with your coworkers to improve your working conditions under your contracting company is your legally protected right under the National Labor Relations Act NLRA. However, certain types of employees (like Independent Contractors on a 1099) do not have these same protections.
To learn more about your workplace organizing right and who is covered, go to https://www.nlrb.gov/rights-we-protect/rights/employee-rights and https://www.nlrb.gov/resources/faq/nlrb.
HELPFUL LINKS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Documentation</title>
      <link>/rights/tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rights/tips/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Start a Job Journal, noting positive and negative comments from supervisors and managers. Keep notes from meetings, schedule changes, etc. Make sure you note when, where, why, etc. Save company memos and pay stubs, ANYTHING that you think will help your case if you must use a government agency to fight the boss.&amp;rdquo; - IWW
All your notes should have the date at the top of each page, and next to any notable action or important statement, jot down the time if possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricks</title>
      <link>/rights/tricks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rights/tricks/</guid>
      <description>TRICKS THEY’LL PULL ON YOU There are a number of reasons behind why contracting is so lucrative for businesses. Some of these decisions are made behind the scenes, but many others are done face-to-face.
HOURS AND PAY Promising contracted employees a certain amount of compensation and then giving them less when it comes time to sign Try to tell you to work without claiming your hours because it will help you get an FTE position (this is wage theft) Placing a higher volume of work, a greater number of hours, and providing less pay to employees with H1B visas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>